

IS Solution Architect Analytics +62816781603 | <u>Linkedin</u> martinsilaban@yahoo.com | <u>Github</u> Jakarta, Indonesia

RESUME OF SILABAN, JOHNY MARTINUS

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Johny Martinus Silaban is a professional with 20 years of experience in Financial Accounting and IT area focusing in ERP and BI Analytics solutions.

As Solution Architect who join Philip Morris International from 2014, I have involved in project implementations, proof of concept (PoC), solution guideline, assessment of new technology and applications.

Before join PMI, I was involved in numerous SAP projects in Tile and Glass Manufacturing, Automotive, Oil and Gas, Telecommunication, and Banking Industry and extensive working on exploring and implementing several financial modules in ERP and BI Analytics area.

Project experience covers analyzing of client business requirement and mapping to the client system, create business process blueprint through business process reengineering, configure according to blue print, propose technical and functional solution, functional and integration testing, preparation of technical specification and coordinating with technical & functional consultant, writing system documentation, program design and testing, knowledge transfer for new IT staffs, trouble-shooting, and conduct training.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

EXPERIENCE

From May 2014 working as Solution Architect in Philip Morris International with responsibilities to designs, implements, manages Company Architecture Services and related service portfolios

15+ implementation, global rollout, upgrade and improvement projects.

Excellence in solution design, solution architecture, implementation and strategy.

Combining an excellent knowledge of the business with extensive and detailed.

Project Management, Team lead of application and development teams

EXPERTISE

Process: Finance Controlling, Planning & Consolidation, System Integration

Technology: SAP (ERP, BI & Analytics, HANA), Cloud, Hadoop

Application: SAP ECC6, SAP BW, SAP BO, Business Planning & Consolidation (BPC), Data Services

(BO-DS), Data Ocean (Hadoop), SAP S/4 HANA, Microsoft BI Stack (Power BI)

CERTIFICATION

SAP Certified Application Associate - SAP S/4HANA for Financial Accounting Associates SAP S/4HANA 1610 (2018)

SAP Certified Associate – SAP S/4HANA Implementation Scenarios for Architects (2018)

SAP Certified Application - Financial Accounting with SAP ERP 6.0 EHP5 (2013)

Registered Accountant in Indonesia Chartered Accountant (1999)

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Financial Accounting

Planning and Budgeting, Reporting and Consolidation, Audit

Information Technology

System Integration, ERP, Reporting and Analytics

Project Management

Vendor Management, Resource Allocation, Quality Assurance, Agile and Scrum

Soft skills

Leadership, Entrepreneurship, Collaboration

WORKING EXPERIENCE

IS SOLUTION ARCHITECT ANALYTICS, , PHILIP MORRIS SAMPOERNA IS CENTER, INDONESIA

March 2018 - ...

IS SOLUTION ARCHITECT ANALYTICS, PHILIP MORRIS MANAGEMENT SA, SWITZERLAND

July 2017 - Feb 2018

IS SOLUTION ARCHITECT SAP FINANCE & BPC, PT. HM SAMPOERNA, INDONESIA

May 2014 – July 2017

SAP PROJECT MANAGER, PERDANA CONSULTING, INDONESIA

May 2012 - May 2014

SAP SEM CONSULTANT, SIEMENS LIMITED, THAILAND

May 2010 - May 2011

SAP SEM BCS CONSULTANT, IBM, INDONESIA

Nov 2009 – May 2010

SAP FICO CONSULTANT, ASTRA GRAPHIA IT, INDONESIA

Nov 2006 - Oct 2009

SAP ECCS CONSULTANT, PST CONSULTING, INDONESIA

Mar 2005 - Oct 2006

FINANCIAL AUDITOR, SOEKRISNO AGOES & PARTNER, INDONESIA

July 2003 – Feb 2005

ADMINISTRATION & LOGISTIC CONTROL LEAD, MAKRO INDONESIA, INDONESIA

Feb 2000 – Oct 2001

JUNIOR AUDITOR, HADIBROTO PUBLIC ACCOUNTING FIRM, INDONESIA

Jun 1999 – Feb 2000

EDUCATION

MASTER DEGREE IN ACCOUNTING, UNIVERSITAS INDONESIA, INDONESIA, 2003 BACHELOR DEGREE IN ACCOUNTING, UNIVERSITAS SUMATRA UTARA, INDONESIA, 1999